<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Mechanics of Online Censorship on ChinaFile</title><link>https://locknet.chinafile.com/additional-materials/the-mechanics-of-online-censorship/</link><description>Recent content in The Mechanics of Online Censorship on ChinaFile</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://locknet.chinafile.com/additional-materials/the-mechanics-of-online-censorship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Internet 101</title><link>https://locknet.chinafile.com/additional-materials/the-mechanics-of-online-censorship/internet-101/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://locknet.chinafile.com/additional-materials/the-mechanics-of-online-censorship/internet-101/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-even-is-the-internet">What Even Is the Internet?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The internet is not one thing, but rather a “network of networks.” A personal computer in Iowa, for example, does not have a single, dedicated wire physically connecting it to the recipe website Epicurious. Nevertheless, an Iowan (let’s call her Marjorie) can get all the recipes she wants simply by pointing her web browser to epicurious.com.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A &lt;strong>network&lt;/strong> is &lt;a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/learning/network-layer/how-does-the-internet-work/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-orange-600 hover:text-orange-700 hover:underline">a group of connected computers that are able to send data to one another&lt;/a>. Marjorie’s request to fetch data from epicurious.com first travels through her immediate network. In Marjorie’s case, this means it goes from her computer to the modem in her home, which then &lt;a href="https://web.stanford.edu/class/msande91si/www-spr04/readings/week1/InternetWhitepaper.htm#:~:text=After%20your%20packets%20traverse%20the,the%20ISP%20buys%20bandwidth%20from." target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-orange-600 hover:text-orange-700 hover:underline">relays&lt;/a> the request to equipment run by her &lt;strong>Internet Service Provider&lt;/strong>, or ISP. (An ISP is an organization that connects users’ home devices to the rest of the internet. Most home users pay a monthly bill to their ISP for internet service. An ISP is often a company, but can sometimes be another type of organization, like a university.)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Censorship: How China Disrupts the Network</title><link>https://locknet.chinafile.com/additional-materials/the-mechanics-of-online-censorship/censorship-how-china-disrupts-the-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://locknet.chinafile.com/additional-materials/the-mechanics-of-online-censorship/censorship-how-china-disrupts-the-network/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="network-level-censorship">Network-Level Censorship&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Chinese authorities have many political, legal, and bureaucratic methods to avoid unwanted information circulating on the country’s domestic internet. They can deny website registration licenses, or mandate that companies such as Apple &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/technology/apple-says-it-is-removing-vpn-services-from-china-app-store-idUSKBN1AE0BX/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-orange-600 hover:text-orange-700 hover:underline">remove&lt;/a> censorship circumvention tools from local app stores. They can also outsource censorship to the online platforms themselves, holding the platforms responsible for any content that appears on their services—a technique known as &lt;strong>service-level censorship&lt;/strong>. (Reports of Weibo or WeChat &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/may/17/chinese-social-media-companies-remove-posts-showing-off-wealth-and-worshiping-money" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-orange-600 hover:text-orange-700 hover:underline">removing content&lt;/a> from their platforms are examples of service-level censorship.)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blocking Circumvention Technologies</title><link>https://locknet.chinafile.com/additional-materials/the-mechanics-of-online-censorship/blocking-circumvention-technologies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://locknet.chinafile.com/additional-materials/the-mechanics-of-online-censorship/blocking-circumvention-technologies/</guid><description>&lt;p>China’s censorship system not only targets “dangerous” content, but also targets users’ attempts to evade the system itself. After all, Beijing spends a lot of money and effort to curate the domestic information environment and keep “dangerous” information outside the country’s digital borders. There would be no point to such an undertaking if it were trivially easy to sidestep the censors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since about 2010, China has put a special premium on hunting down and blocking information about and access to censorship circumvention tools. The censors are engaged in a seemingly endless arms race with circumvention tool developers, who try to create countermeasures after each new block. (It is worth mentioning that Chinese authorities do not block every single possible circumvention tool. Bowing to economic necessity, the government maintains a list of &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/chinas-vpn-crackdown-may-aid-government-surveillance-1516189155" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-orange-600 hover:text-orange-700 hover:underline">approved technologies&lt;/a> that allow foreign businesses and others to circumvent the censorship system in order to send secure emails or visit blocked websites. These approved circumvention tools also likely allow the government to surveil communications sent within them.)&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>