<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Additional Materials on ChinaFile</title><link>https://locknet2.netlify.app/additional-materials/</link><description>Recent content in Additional Materials on ChinaFile</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://locknet2.netlify.app/additional-materials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Executive Summary</title><link>https://locknet2.netlify.app/additional-materials/executive-summary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://locknet2.netlify.app/additional-materials/executive-summary/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;a href="https://www.chinafile.com/sites/default/files/locknet_executive_summary.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="text-orange-600 hover:text-orange-700 hover:underline">Download a PDF of this Executive Summary&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/br>
&lt;p>China, its companies, and its citizens play a major role in the global internet: producing infrastructure, services, and content upon which people around the world depend. Yet, China’s extensive online censorship system remains poorly understood by most of the internet’s users, and the ways it alters both the physical and digital architecture of the internet are too often overlooked.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more than a year, ChinaFile Senior Editor for Investigations Jessica Batke and Northeastern University Assistant Professor Laura Edelson explored how China censors its internet, interviewing experts, reviewing decades of computer science research, and tracking policy and regulatory changes over time. Their cross-disciplinary approach afforded them a broad view of the interplay between the technological and social aspects of China’s censorship regime, yielding new insights about the system’s purpose, its capacity, and its likely trajectory in the years to come. It also allowed them to clear up longstanding misconceptions and establish new frameworks for future research.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Glossary</title><link>https://locknet2.netlify.app/additional-materials/glossary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://locknet2.netlify.app/additional-materials/glossary/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Application layer&lt;/strong> - The part of the network stack that conducts high-level data management and translation, such as character encoding, data compression, encryption/decryption, and remote file access. &lt;strong>HTTP&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>HTTPS protocols&lt;/strong> function at this layer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Border Gateway Protocol (BGP)&lt;/strong> - The set of rules governing how one router at the edge of a network communicates with a router in a neighboring network. This allows the routers to provide and receive information about the status of each others’ networks, such as what paths are available in the neighboring network. This helps them decide what paths they might use to transmit packets.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Notes on China from a Computer Scientist</title><link>https://locknet2.netlify.app/additional-materials/notes-on-china/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://locknet2.netlify.app/additional-materials/notes-on-china/</guid><description>&lt;p>The goal of this project is to explain both &lt;em>how&lt;/em> China has built such an effective system for controlling the flow of information on the internet and &lt;em>why&lt;/em> its leaders are willing to go to such lengths to do so. I’m a computer scientist, so the technical side of this enterprise seemed relatively straightforward, but I initially found myself quite puzzled at the rationale behind China’s censorship as a whole. Like a lot of folks with degrees in the sciences, during college I was required to take exactly one history class (I chose Modern European History) and I knew little about China before beginning this project. However, as I learned more about the country’s political system and how the Chinese Communist Party (CCP) has held onto power, its approach to online censorship felt less perplexing.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>